# Kartik Chawla

# **CONTACT**

**Phone:** (705) 500-4371

**Email:** kchawla1995@gmail.com **Location:** Toronto, Ontario

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>GitHub</u>

Website

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- JS Frameworks: Angular (14),
   React.js
- Front-End Skills: HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, JavaScript, TypeScript
- JavaScript Expertise
- Web Development
- SSR: Angular Universal, Next.js
- Unit Testing Frameworks:
   Jasmine, Karma, Jest
- React Native
- Kotlin Android
- Swift using Storyboard / SwiftUI - iOS
- NGRX, Redux
- Responsive Designs: Bootstrap, Material UI
- End-to-End Testing: Cypress
- Databases: Oracle, SQL, MongoDB
- Cloud Computing: AWS, GCP
- Backend JS Framework: Node.JS
- Restful API, GraphQL
- Source and Version Control:
   Git, GitHub, Gitlab, BitBucket
- Scrum, Agile Methodology
- JIRA
- Core Web Vitals
- SEO

#### PROFESSIONAL STATEMENT

Highly analytical, efficient full-stack developer with experience in MEAN, MERN, UX/UI, AWS, GCP, Heroku and RESTful APIs. Excels at analyzing business requirements, creating technical solutions and collaborating with stakeholders while working within Agile, crossfunctional teams. Committed to driving innovative improvements in software applications, Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) and company processes to optimize efficiency.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Freelance

#### June 2022 - December 2022

## JavaScript and TypeScript Developer

- Utilized Angular, React.js and TypeScript frameworks to design, develop and implement high-quality and high-performance web applications to meet client requirements.
- Designed and developed several multi-tier projects, and provided end-to-end support including inventory management, online store interfaces and payment processing systems.
- Tested UX across devices and platforms to unify customer experiences and provide a seamless user experience.
- Developed and implemented automated unit and integration testing through Jest and Cypress frameworks to ensure stability of code during development.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including back-end developers, to ensure seamless integration and optimal performance.
- Implemented Sonar and Jenkins scripts and re-organized branch strategies to streamline the original CI/CD solution at the company.

#### **EPAM Systems**

#### April 2021 - April 2022

# Senior Software Engineer

- Curated exceptional web user experiences through utilization of the latest versions of Angular framework, and leveraged NgRx stores to simplify and improve the user journey.
- Standardized design patterns across the company though the use of a backwards compatible central data exchange (CDX) library, providing a consistent design framework and allowing for efficient and effective data transfer between project components.
- Interfaced with stakeholders, leveraging Storyboard to prototype and demo in an easy to digest manner, helping to minimize communication gaps.
- Leveraged AWS Lambda and Node.js to create data-driven reports, triggered through custom scripts deployed to the company's CI/CD pipelines.
- Developed, tested and implemented a new software library to transform Power BI slicer data into a form resembling Data Analysis Expressions (DAX) queries, enabling extraction of complex data.
- Wrote and maintained testing in Jest and Jasmine to achieve 95% code coverage, and generate LCOV reports to locate bugs, cognitive complexity and code smells through SonarQube.

## **EDUCATION**

Georgian College of Applied Arts and Technology, Barrie, Ontario Post-Degree Certificate: Mobile Application Development December 2022

- MDEV Student Representative
   Professional Advisory
   Committee (PAC)
- Graduated with Honors: 95%
- ➤ GPA: 4.0

Maharaja Agrasen University, India Bachelor of Technology:
Computer Science and
Engineering
May 2017

# **LANGUAGES**

• Fluent: English, Hindi

# **AWARDS & HONORS**

#### **EPAM Systems**

- Above and Beyond, January 2022
- JS Contributor, December 2021
- Team Player, July 2021
- Pat on the Back,
   June 2021

# Kellton Tech Solutions Private Limited

- Role Model,
   February 2021
- Most Valuable Player, July 2020
- Role Model, September 2019
- Star of The Quarter, June 2019
- Marketing Superhero, September 2018

#### **Kellton Tech Solutions Pvt Ltd**

**February 2017 - April 2021** 

**Senior Software Engineer,** August 2019 - April 2021

- Led several teams on a variety of projects, often spanning multiple time zones, ensuring on-time completion of deliverables within budget.
- Contributed to the success of a leading insurance company in Dublin, Ireland, by creating high-performing and secure Home, Motor and Travel Insurance websites.
- Implemented Agile methodology and served as Scrum master throughout the product life cycle.
- Managed multiple intricate projects, leveraging strong proficiency in RxJS and NgRx to create and support intuitive and simple UX in online stores.
- Deployed AWS cloud-based applications with an emphasis on scalability.
- Streamlined and improved CI/CD infrastructure through development work in Jenkins, SonarQube and Bitbucket.
- Developed training curriculum and led daily courses for 70+ employees on a variety of topics, focusing on personal and professional development and ensuring employees were supplied with up-to-date organizational and technical knowledge.

#### **Software Engineer,** February 2017 - August 2019

- Created various proof of concepts to help with client acquisition and demonstration, and championed solutions to facilitate company adoption.
- Contributed to numerous complex frontend projects focusing on web store interfaces and data management using NGRX, RXJS and Redux.
- Collaborated with industry-leading global food chains to design and develop E-Commerce applications using Angular, JavaScript, HTML and CSS.
- Deployed company-wide training opportunities for 50 employees on topics such as SCRUM, Github, JavaScript, Angular, React.js, Node.js, etc.